siliconbeachtraining.co.uk 2019-05-14

# Silicon Beach Training Privacy Policy

## Who we are?

Silicon Beach Training Limited (hereafter referred to as the “Company”, “we”, “us”, and “our”) provides professional training courses. The Company takes data protection very seriously and abide by the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). We encourage prospective clients to read the Company’s terms and conditions, prior to any purchases, in parallel to this privacy statement.

## What data we collect?

We collect the following information from you through the use of enquiry and contact forms on the Website, and within Emails or telephone communications too:

  * Name and contact data: We collect your first and last name, email address, postal address, phone number, in order to respond sufficiently and appropriately to your enquiry to find a suitable course for you.
  * Billing data: We collect data necessary billing information to process your payment if you make a purchase. We do not store or retain any payment details once the purchase is complete.

If you are progressing your career through the Company, Apprenticeship or further education we may collect addition personal information to secure funding or to satisfy statutory legal or Government scheme requirements. You will be informed on such occasions.

We also store personal information from you when you communicate with us regarding the provision of services, including by email, postal mail or telephone.

We collect certain information about the visitors of our Website. Please refer to Cookies policy for more details.

We do not pass on training information to any other organisation, or your personal organisation, without the explicit consent of your employer, unless required by our examining institutes in the pursuit of service delivery, for example when registering an exam.

If you do not wish to be contacted for any marketing purposes your consent can be removed by clicking “unsubscribe” on our formal marketing emails. An alternative is to log your request to unsubscribe by visiting our “[Unsubscribe me](http://unsubscribe.thetekhub.com/unsubscribe/silicon-beach-training)” page.

## Use of data collected

The information that we collect and store relating to you is primarily used to enable us to provide our Services to you. Additionally, we may use the information for the following purposes:

  * To provide you with information you request from us
  * To maintain the account you create or use on our Website
  * To process your booking and purchase
  * To respond to your queries efficiently
  * To provide information on other products and Services which we feel may be of interest to you in line with your communications preferences
  * To meet our contractual commitments to you
  * To act on your behalf where third party funding is available and appropriate
  * To act on your behalf where the Service is delivered to you with the help of external providers/ third parties
  * To notify you about any changes to the Website and/or our Services that may have an impact on your actions
  * To notify you of similar products that may be of interest to you
  * To process your examination, we may need to transfer your data to examination institutes including PeopleCert, APM, APMG, The Open Group, NEBOSH, EC Council, and Microsoft.

## Lawful Basis for Processing Data

There are three causes for the Company to process personal data, including:

  * Fulfilling a contractual agreement – if you purchase a product, either a book, exam or course, the Company shall process your data sufficiently and only where appropriate in servicing the prevailing agreement. Such processing includes sending your name and email address to the relevant examination institutes for the purpose of providing your exam, marking your exam, and providing you with the certificate, where appropriate.
  * Legitimate Interests – if you have purchased a product from the Company, we may process your data and contact you if we believe we can enhance your career with a similar product. Please see our “Direct Marketing” term for further details.
  * Consent – if you give us explicit consent to contact you regarding an enquiry or for direct marketing purposes, we shall contact you via only the mediums consented to. Please see our “Consent” term for further details.

## Direct Marketing

The Company will rely on the GDPR’s legitimate interests clause and/or PECR’s Soft Opt-in to send direct marketing communication, in the form of emails and telephone calls, to market similar courses to customers that have purchased our services. Such advertisement within the direct marketing shall be similar to the product purchased, in accordance with the expectations of the customer. Our Company’s interest is to develop our business, whilst providing learning and career development opportunities to our customers. Given the nature of the service provision, we do not expect the rights or freedoms of the data subjects to be at risk to harm.

## Consent

By using our websites or agreeing to do business with us you consent to the collection and use of information as outlined within this page and as informed at the point of data entry too with explicit statements of consent and tick boxes.

If you have any concerns regarding your personal information that we may hold please contact us using the URL given at the bottom of this page.

## Information We Share

We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal data that you provide to us or that we collect, except as described within this statement, including to examination institutes or providers within the delivery of the service, in accordance with our privacy policy. Personal data that you provide directly to us will be apparent from the context in which you provide it, for example, if you purchase a course with an exam, you should expect your details to be passed on to the relevant examination institute; if you submit an enquiry, no such data shall be transferred. We may share personal data with service providers that perform services, in this case, all service providers have entered into legally binding agreements require them to use or disclose personal data only as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with applicable legal requirements. To summarise, we may share personal data you provide to us or that we collect with other entities within Silicon Beach Training Limited's Group and service providers to perform our contractual agreements.

In addition, we may disclose personal data about you if we are required or permitted to do so by law or legal process, for example, due to a court order or request from a law enforcement agency when we believe the disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss.

## Storing, Managing, and Transferring data

The personal information that we collect is stored centrally on secure servers within the EU.

The Company has a strict data retention policy, where it has a justifiable business or legitimate legal reason to store data. Data with no legal or business purpose to retain, is erased with immediate effect and is not stored. Please note that the transmission of information via the internet (including email) is not completely secure and therefore, although we endeavour to protect the personal information you provide to us, we cannot guarantee the security of data sent to us electronically and the transmission of such data is therefore entirely at your own risk.

The Company shall process data in accordance with the relevant provisions in your county, for example if you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA), the GDPR shall be adhered to and your data protected accordingly. If an international transfer of data must take place in order to provide the service agreed, data shall only be transferred where:

  * The applicable country meets the requirements and has therefore been granted a European Commission on Adequacy
  * A US-EU Privacy Shield Exists
  * Appropriate safeguards have been applied, such as a EU Model Contract

## Your Rights – Access, Erasure, Portability, and Rectification

## Exercising Your Data Rights

Should you wish to access or update the personal information that we hold about you please contact us using the URL below or via email to submit a Subject Access Request.

You can view, edit or delete your personal data you might have provided in prior communication with the Company, by exercising your Right to Erasure or Rectification. How you can access or control your personal data will depend on which products you use and what communication medium it is on.

You can always choose whether you wish to receive promotional emails or promotions through telephone calls. You can also unsubscribe from receiving interest-based advertising from us by visiting our “[Unsubscribe Me](http://unsubscribe.thetekhub.com/unsubscribe/silicon-beach-training)” page or by contacting [data.officers@siliconbeachtraining.co.uk](mailto:data.officers@siliconbeachtraining.co.uk)

Internal access to data is only granted to privileged users, to ensure security. In addition, appropriate security measures are implemented to ensure the security of your personal data.

Where you have given us consent to process your data, you can retract this consent, by sending an appropriate email to [data.officers@siliconbeachtraining.co.uk](mailto:data.officers@siliconbeachtraining.co.uk "Send us email")

## **Updates to our Notice**

We may update this privacy statement periodically, in accordance with the updates to relevant data protection laws. Such updates will not be notified, so it is advised you check the statement upon every purchase.

## Contractors and Suppliers

Subject matter contractors are occasionally utilised by the Company to ensure that service is of the expected quality. It is essential that all staff, contractors, and clients are confident that any data processed in relation to them will be processed in accordance with the GDPR. Employees of the Company are required to process data in relation to other employees, contractors, and clients in accordance with your GDPR training and with the provisions of the GDPR. The Company adheres to stringent data protection and encryption procedures that ensure that personal and sensitive data is protected – during both processing and the storage of data.

## Use of cookies and other technologies

## Cookies on our website

The Company may use following cookies on this website for the purposes mentioned:

### User session cookie

We may use a session cookie so that we can remember what is in your shopping basket and remember where you are in the order process.

### Analytical/performance cookies

They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.

### Targeting cookies

These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

### Refusing cookies

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies.

In Google Chrome, you can adjust the cookies settings by clicking the Menu > settings > Show advanced settings > In the "Privacy" section, click Content settings > Use the "Cookies" section to change your settings.

In Internet Explorer, you can refuse all cookies by clicking “Tools”, “Internet Options”, “Privacy”, and selecting “Block all cookies” using the sliding selector. 

In Firefox, you can adjust your cookies settings by clicking “Tools”, “Options” and “Privacy”.

Please note that blocking/refusing cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of our website.

## Use of Analytics modules

We use Google analytics within our Website to monitor how visitors move around the website and how they reached it and use it. This is done so that we can see total (not individual) statistics on which types of content users access most frequently. The Google cookies also tell us if you have visited the site before and allow us to track how many individual users the websites have. The Google cookies cannot be used to identify individuals - they are only used for statistical purposes only. You can opt out of Google cookies here <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> 

From time to time we may have links to other services such as Social media or video services on our sites. These services may drop cookies on your computer when you use them, especially if you are already logged into their service. Due to the nature of how cookies work we cannot access these cookies nor control their use. Likewise, these 3rd party services cannot access our session or analytics cookies. 

or email to [data.officers@siliconbeachtraining.co.uk](mailto:data.officers@siliconbeachtraining.co.uk "Send us email")
